{"tossups": [{"question": "A colony in this country was governed by Burnaby\u2019s Code and faced the Spanish attack of the Battle of St. George\u2019s Caye. George Price led this country\u2019s People United party, where logwood was once heavily extracted by the English. This country is the site of the Mayan city of Caracol. The British maintained troops in this country after this country\u2019s 1981 independence to deter claims from neighboring Guatemala. For ten points, name this country once known as British Honduras, which has its capital at Belmopan.", "answer": "<b> Belize</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Dusty Baker and Glenn Burke played for this team in 1977 when they supposedly invented the high five. Mayor Norris Poulson reversed city plans for the Elysian Park Heights public housing development in favor of giving land in Chavez Ravine to Walter O\u2019Malley, the owner of this team. This team\u2019s fans have a reputation for arriving late and leaving games early, in large part due to traffic nightmares on the 110 Freeway and Sunset Boulevard. For ten points, name this Major League Baseball team that, after 1957, moved from Brooklyn to Los Angeles.", "answer": "Los Angeles<b> Dodgers</b> (accept Brooklyn<b> Dodgers</b> after \u201cNorris\u201d is read; prompt on \u201cLos Angeles\u201d; prompt on \u201cBrooklyn\u201d after \u201cNorris\u201d is read)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "Negotiations for this treaty began after one side invoked promises made to them in the papal bull <em>Aeterni regis</em>. Two bulls named<em> Inter caetera</em> preceded this treaty and were amended by<em> Dudum siquidem</em>, which was rejected since it excluded John II from India. Pope Alexander VI helped mediate this treaty that granted Brazil to one party, following a demarcation line 370 leagues west of Cape Verde. For ten points, identify this treaty that divided the New World between Spain and Portugal.", "answer": "Treaty of<b> Tordesillas</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "In a meeting with Golda Meir, this man argued that if the Soviet Union were to put Jews into gas chambers that it was \u201cnot an American concern.\u201d This politician labeled Indira Gandhi a \u201cwitch\u201d and claimed that \u201cthe Indians are bastards\u201d after siding with Bangladesh in a 1971 war. In the Halloween Massacre, this man was removed as Gerald Ford\u2019s National Security Adviser but was allowed to maintain his role as Secretary of State. For ten points, name this American statesman who won the 1973 Nobel Peace Prize for negotiating a ceasefire in Vietnam.", "answer": "Henry<b> Kissinger</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "The Tummal Inscription verified this mythical person\u2019s existence. Nancy Sandars\u2019 translation of the most famous work about this man notes that Gudea may have conflated his achievements with this man. This \u201ctwo-thirds divine, one-third mortal\u201d is challenged to stay awake in order to obtain a plant that grants immortality by Utnapishtim. This man slays Humbaba in the Cedar Forest with his best friend, Enkidu. For ten points, name this protagonist of a namesake Mesopotamian epic.", "answer": "<b> Gilgamesh</b> Page 1", "metadata": "Mythology - Mythology"}, {"question": "After being denied membership from this state\u2019s Thule Society, Anton Arco-Valley assassinated Kurt Eisner, a leader of this state\u2019s Soviet Republic. Ashkenazi Jews were targeted during the 1819 Hep-Hep riots in this state. Prince Liutpold ruled as regent for one monarch of this state after the latter was declared insane. The 1918 Anif declaration ended seven centuries of Wittelsbach rule over, for ten points, what German state that saw \u201cMad King\u201d Ludwig II\u2019s rule from its capital at Munich?", "answer": "<b> Bavaria</b> (or<b> Bayern</b>, accept descriptions of \u201ckingdom or \u201csocialist republic\u201d)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "During this period, Frank Reid was killed in a shootout with Jesse Murphy. Soapy Smith created a scam telegraph service during this period which faked its replies. Robert Henderson inadvertently sparked this period by advising Skookum Jim to explore Rabbit\u2019s Creek. People participating in this event would often travel from Skagway before continuing on the Chikoot and White passes. Dawson City became a boom town due to, for ten points, what 19th century event in which prospectors flocked to the Yukon River?", "answer": "<b> Klondike</b> Gold Rush (accept<b> Yukon</b> Gold Rush before \u201cYukon River\u201d is read)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "These objects are required to have an ushnisha indentation. 6,666 of these objects rest at the feet of a giant one of these objects at the Spring Temple. An emerald one of these objects has its outfits changed by the King of Thailand each season. 504 of these objects are located at Borobudur in Java. The subjects of these objects include Amitabha and Gautama. For 10 points, name these religious objects often carved by Mahayana and Theravada followers.", "answer": "<b> statue</b>s of<b> Buddha</b>", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {"question": "Zhang Chai started the \u201cCase of the Wooden Staff Assault\u201d by breaking into the palace of a ruler of this dynasty. The last emperor of this dynasty hung himself at the \u201cguilty pagoda tree\u201d and was the Chongzhen Emperor. This dynasty\u2019s fall began after the Seven Grievances were proclaimed by Nurhachi. One emperor from this dynasty created a namesake encyclopedia and sent Zheng He to Sri Lanka. The Yongle Emperor ruled, for ten points, what dynasty that was succeeded by the Qing?", "answer": "<b> Ming</b> Dynasty Page 2", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "In the prelude to this event, David Blair was reassigned but failed to return a storage locker key. Lord Mersey led an investigation into this event which found that J. Bruce Ismay was justified in escaping it. William Murdoch may have committed suicide near the end of this event. Wallace Hartley led a band during this event which may have played \u201cNearer, My God, to Thee.\u201d Captain Edward Smith died during this event having last been seen entering the wheelhouse. For ten points, name this 1912 disaster in which an \u201cunsinkable\u201d ship struck an iceberg.", "answer": "<b> Sinking</b> of the RMS<b> Titanic</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "Shah Ashraf Ghilji, a leader of a dynasty in this nation, beat the Safavids at the Battle of Gulnabad. Besides the Hotakis, a man known as the Iron Amir ruled this nation and crushed the Hazara revolts. This nation\u2019s disputed border with Pakistan, the Durand Line, was established to make this nation a buffer zone between England and Russia. The Mughals disputed this country\u2019s region of Kandahar. For ten points, name this Middle Eastern nation governed from Kabul.", "answer": "<b> Afghanistan</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This political ideology was influenced by one manifesto by Filippo Tommaso Marinetti, who argued modernization required youth, speed, and war. According to one definition, this ideology\u2019s \u201cgoals\u201d include a regulated economy and its \u201cstyle\u201d includes promoting masculinity, hero worship, and violence. This ideology took its name from a symbol of Roman magistrates\u2019 authority, a bundle of sticks tied around an axe. For ten points, name this authoritarian ideology exemplified by Mussolini and Hitler.", "answer": "<b> fascism</b>", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This composer depicted his country\u2019s industrialization in the ballet<em> The Steel Step</em>. Another ballet by this composer includes dances for four fairies each depicting a season. This composer of the film scores for<em> Alexander Nevsky</em> and<em> Ivan the Terrible</em> wrote a ballet containing a \u201cDance of the Knights.\u201d Another work by this composer sees the bassoon represent a grandfather and the oboe represent a duck. For ten points, name this Russian composer of<em> Peter and the Wolf</em>.", "answer": "Sergei<b> Prokofiev</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {}, {"question": "During this conflict, one leader declared \u201cif they won\u2019t eat, let them drink!\u201d before throwing sacred chickens overboard at the Battle of Drepana. The Battle of the Aegates Islands was the last naval battle of this conflict, which ended with the Treaty of Lutatius. This conflict\u2019s Battle of Mylae included the first use of a boarding bridge called the corvus. Hanno the Great and Hamilcar Barca led the losing side in, for ten points, what first major war fought between Rome and Carthage?", "answer": "<b> First Punic War</b> (prompt on \u201cPunic War\u201d)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "The medieval ports of Harfleur and Honfleur controlled access to this river until the foundation of Le Havre on the mouth of this river. This river\u2019s tributaries include the Oise [waz] and Eure rivers, and this river\u2019s maritime section begins after it passes Rouen. The Canal Saint-Martin connects to, for ten points, what river, which is crossed by the Pont des Beaux-Arts and the Pont Neuf in Paris?", "answer": "The<b> Seine</b> River", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "<b>The name of an operation during this conflict was changed due to the different ways two countries spelled \u201cHamilcar.\u201d This conflict\u2019s Operation (+) Musketeer featured a successful amphibious landing at Port Said [sai-eed]. Canadian Prime Minister Lester Pearson was awarded a Nobel Peace Prize for his role in resolving this conflict, which forced (*)</b> Anthony Eden to resign. This conflict included a combined Anglo-French naval assault and an Israeli attack on the Sinai Peninsula. For ten points, name this 1956 conflict which broke out after Nasser nationalized a namesake canal.", "answer": "<b> Suez Crisis</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man delivered one address upon arriving at Terowie railway station. This military</b> <b>commander ignored orders to execute Rainbow Five after the initial (+)</b> <b>Pearl Harbor</b> <b>attacks. The first modern Purple Heart was awarded to this man, who spearheaded its reintroduction in 1932. This man fled with his wife, Jean Marie, to (*)</b> Corregidor after being expelled from Luzon by the Japanese. For ten points, name this U.S. five star general who declared \u201cI shall return\u201d upon escaping to Australia from the Philippines and served as Supreme Commander of Allied Forces in postwar Japan.", "answer": "Douglas<b> MacArthur</b> Page 9", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>This event was preceded by a diversionary attack on Mount Holly as part of the Battle</b> <b>of Iron Works Hill. The Marblehead Regiment, mainly composed of (+)</b> <b>fisherman, were</b> <b>key in this event but still disbanded just a few days later. Misinformation spread by John Honeyman facilitated this event. In the prelude to this event, Thomas Paine\u2019s</b><em><b> The (*) </b></em><b>American Crisis</b> was read to soldiers to bolder their morale. In the fighting after the success of this event, James Monroe nearly died from a severed artery. For ten points, name this maneuver carried out by George Washington before the Battle of Trenton.", "answer": "<b> Washington cross</b>ing the<b> Delaware</b> (prompt on the Battle of Trenton before it is read) Page 10", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}], "bonuses": []}